

Gil Cunha

Date of birth: 11/07/1997 | **Nationality:** Portuguese | (+351) 915345048 |

gilffcunha@gmail.com http://gilffcunha.github.io/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/gilcunha97/ | Skype: gil.cunha365 |

Rua Padre António Vieira, nº55, 4800-080, Guimarães, Portugal

About me:

Having achieved a Master's Degree in Informatics Engineering at the University of Minho (www.uminho.pt),

I'm a person who enjoys working in a team and has good communication with his colleagues. I work hard to accomplish my objectives, always trying to give the best quality and efficiency to the projects/products of my company.

I consider myself a Software & Big Data Engineer, having experience in coding with several programming languages, mainly Java and Python. However, I'm also keen on Data Engineering, Software Architecture and Business Intelligence areas.

WORK EXPERIENCE

26/09/2021 – CURRENT – Lisbon, Portugal

BIG DATA ENGINEER - XPAND IT

- Migration of several on-premise projects to cloud, using Azure technologies (Data Factory, Databricks, etc), for a multinational financial services company
- Management of ETL (Extraction, Transformation & Load) processes in order to prepare data to be consumed by ML models for marketing campaigns
- Manage cloud processes to treat data to be used in the analysis and improvement of a Contact Center platform

07/09/2020 - 23/09/2021 - Braga, Portugal

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - BSOLUS- BUSINESS SOLUTIONS, LDA

- E-commerce platforms (online stores) maintenance
- Development of the Marketing Automation system based on microservices workflow orchestration, using BPMN 2.0.

23/11/2019 - 23/08/2020 - Braga, Portugal

WEB ENGINEER - BSOLUS- BUSINESS SOLUTIONS, LDA

- Professional Internship
- Development of a recommendation system and data analysis for e-commerce platforms (online stores).

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

10/09/2015 - 21/02/2021 - Braga, Portugal

MASTER'S DEGREE IN INFORMATICS ENGINEERING - University of Minho

Field(s) of study

Computer science

Thesis: Data Analysis and Recommender System Architecture for E-Commerce Platforms

16 | EQF level 7 | https://www.uminho.pt/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **PORTUGUESE**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1
SPANISH	B1	B1	A2	A2	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

ELK (Elasticsearch Logstash Kibana) | Business Intelligence | RESTful Webservices | Agile (Scrum) | Python | Java | Big Data | Docker | Data, Web & Software Engineering | E-commerce | NodeJS | Azure Datafactory | Azure Databricks | MongoDB | MySQL | Apache Spark | Microservices | Restful APIs | Cloud computing

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

03/11/2020 - 05/11/2020 - Guimarães, Portugal

21st International Conference on Intelligent Data Engineering and Automated Learning (IDEAL 2020)

http://islab.di.uminho.pt/ideal2020/

Lisboa, Portugal

Pixels Camp 2017

https://pixels.camp/

University of Minho, Gualtar, Braga, Portugal

Google HashCode 2017

https://codingcompetitions.withgoogle.com/hashcode/

University of Minho, Gualtar, Braga, Portugal

Computer Engineering Week and Informatics Days, at the University of Minho (SEI 2017)

https://www.facebook.com/SEI.UMinho/

Lisboa, Portugal

Web Summit 2016

https://websummit.com/

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Organization skills

• Strict, demanding and competent, prioritizing the various tasks of the projects, in order to distribute and carry out each function effectively, accomplishing the deadlines.

- I have a high sense of organization and responsibility, always aiming to design an efficient and high-quality final product.
- All these attributes have been enhanced, over the years, by academic projects, extra-curricular events and professional work.

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication and social skills

- Adequate communication and relationship with co-workers, promoting team spirit and the level of professionalism
- Easy integration in diverse work environments
- Cooperative, in order to provide greater efficiency in the development of projects, as well as well-being in the workplace

WORK SKILLS

Work skills

- I'm able to plan, develop, implement and manage various types of databases, mastering the concepts in this area.
- I also hold knowledge about the concepts of Machine Learning and Business Intelligence as well as experience in their application, having an interest in the areas of data collection and analysis. Experienced in working with Data Mining tools, to develop forecasting models and neural networks.

PUBLICATIONS

Improving Performance of Recommendation System Architecture

10.1007/978-3-030-62365-4_47 https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-62365-4_47 = 2020